# Mehmet Alp Karatepe Computer Engineering Student

Last update: October 30, 2022

Up-to-date version of CV is available at

https://synwix.github.io/cv

Residence: Ankara, Turkey

LinkedIn: in Mehmet Alp Karatepe

Email: <u>m.alp.krtp@gmail.com</u>

JavaScript	++++	React	++++	Redux	++++	Next.js	++++	Node	++++	GraphQL	+++
								JS			
Git	++++	HTML	++++	CSS	++++	SASS	++++	Tailwind	++++	npm	++++
Webpack	++++	Java	++++	C#	+++	C/C++	+++	Python	++++	Firebase	++
Matlab	+	Django	++	Keras	++++	Tensorflow	/ ++++	.NET	+		

Extensive knowledge of Data Structures and Algorithms, Object-Oriented Programming and Machine Learning. 2 years of experience with JavaScript, React, Redux-Saga, SASS and Tailwind, Node.js, Next.js for Fullstack Development and Java, C, C# and Python. 4 years of study and experience on Machine Learning with Tensorflow and Keras, I also have several certificates from the Stanford Universities Machine Learning professor Andrew Ng's courses. I'm experienced in Front-end and Back-end engineering with 2 years of experience, with the usage of several frameworks such as React, Redux-Saga, Next.js, Node.js and MongoDB. Really interested in building SaaS products and the SaaS ecosystem.

# **Professional Experience**

### Software Engineer Internship at JotForm

Internship as a Front-End Developer at JotForm between Sep 2022 - Now jotform.com

Working an a project in a team of four as the Frontend Developer of the said team.

# Software Engineer Internship at JotForm

4 Months of Internship as a Full-Stack Developer at JotForm between Jan 2022 - Apr 2022 jotform.com

Worked on two projects, both on which I have used GraphQL, Apollo, Monorepo technologies such as nx, React and Redux on front-end and NodeJS with express on the back-end. I have deployed several applications for inhouse use of the company with the use of Vercel.

```
JavaScript React JS Redux-Saga GraphQL NodeJS Express Apollo HTML CSS Nx Monorepo
```

### Software Engineer Internship at JotForm

4 Months of Internship as a Front-End Developer at JotForm between May 2021 - Sep 2021 jotform.com

Worked with a team of developers on a project that lasted for 4 months from start to finish as the front-end developer of the team. I have used JS, React and Redux-Saga for side effect management. Worked together closely with the back-end developer, UI Developer and the designer of our team, from which I have gained a great experience at front-end development, project management and working as a team on a project.

## Chat-App

Full-Stack Web App https://chat-app-alp.netlify.app/

The Web Application that I developed with the use of JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS in Front-End and with the usage of Chat Engine as the Back-End to store messages in real-time, at which I used JS to communicate with the API. You can test my web app with Username: Tester and Password: Tester.

```
JavaScript React JS HTML CSS Chat Engine API
```

### **Teknofest Machine Learning Competition**

Machine Learning Competition

We were a finalist with our team in a Machine Learning competition project as a group in Teknofest, which involves object detection we use Keras to develop a Machine Learning model for.

Keras Tensorflow Machine Learning Research

### Skills

#### **Frontend**

I have used JavaScript, React, Redux, Next.js, SASS, Tailwind and Redux-Saga for side effect management on big web application projects, and I consistently learn and follow new tools in this field, have used Vercel and Railway.app for deploment. Many times, I have used Figma used by the designer of my team to help the design process.

#### **Backend**

I have used backend frameworks for big web application projects such as NodeJS and Rails with MongoDB and Django, and backend services such as Firebase and AWS, and I consistently learn new frameworks and tools.

#### **Data Structures and Algorithms**

The Programming, Computer Science and Discrete Mathematics for Computer Science courses has taught me the ability of Algorithmic thinking by both theory and applying.

#### **Machine Learning**

I studied in a Machine Learning bootcamp at Datajarlabs, and also have taken an online course of Machine Learning by Andrew Ng from Stanford University. I have been reading research papers in the field from various resources. I have done a project on Exploratory Data Analysis and done many assignments regarding model training with Linear Regression and Logistics Regression, and Boosting Algorithms at the bootcamp of Datajarlabs. Here.

#### **Java Programming**

I programmed in Java for a year before my first year and I have taken two programming courses in two semesters, both in java, done several projects as assignments and as well as side projects.

#### **C Programming**

I have taken a Systems Programming course which also had C programming in its syllabus, which I learned extensively myself apart from the course work.

#### **Linux and Shell**

All my courses on Programming and Algorithms required using linux as the OS for their labs and lessons. The Systems Programming class was focused mostly on unix and linux, consisting of unix kernel, shell, file system, shell programming, task control, signal capture and communication between tasks.

### Education

TOBB ETU Computer Engineering Bachelor's Degree [2019 - 2023]

# Languages

Turkish - Native

English - C2/Fluent

### Certifications

- Introduction to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning Coursera 6MCXCNUV5EVQ 01 May 2020
- Convolutional Neural Networks in TensorFlow Coursera WJLWN37S3Y8Z 03 May 2020
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning Coursera 4WZPHXYKWVVG 16 May 2020
- <u>Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization Coursera MAN527VXLGZ8</u> 18 May 2020
- <u>Structuring Machine Learning Projects Coursera UBJU3C5GN8AX 19 May 2020</u>
- <u>Convolutional Neural Networks Coursera 6C6FKPLZEXH8</u> 25 May 2020